Register of the Edward Geary Lansdale papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound Recordings, 1951-1975
  - Speeches, seminars, panels, and interviews, 1954-1971, undated
    - Tape 124, United States, 1971 October 8
      The interviewer says that he has done some reading since the last time he and General Lansdale talked, and he has some questions. The first topic he brings up is the concept of "personalism," which is a concept, philosophy, or technique which was related to politics (of the Diem regime) in South Vietnam. The two discuss Diem and his relationship to the people of Vietnam, and Diem's use of radio to provide information to the people. Lansdale discusses personalism and individuals from Vietnam's past. He also brings up Communist organizational techniques, which were adopted (in part) by other parties and even by the Saigon government.
      The two then talk about Vietnam under French rule and the difficulties the people in public office had in getting along with the citizens of Vietnam. The public officials were perhaps too anxious to use their authority, because they had had none before (like the newly-arrived Irish immigrants to the U.S., who became policemen).
      General Lansdale then talks about Confucianism and its strong influence in Vietnam. The interviewer asks a question about what he thinks might be an "Oriental custom" -- bringing in a third party, if negotiations between two people break down. General Lansdale points out that this is not a custom particular to the Vietnamese and says that Americans newly-arrived in Vietnam often find the culture so exotic that they don't think of the Vietnamese as humans who are more like than unlike other people.
      General Lansdale talks about the strategic hamlet program in Vietnam and in the Philippines.
      The interviewer brings up a new subject -- what is referred to in the Pentagon Papers as "grey broadcasts." These are evidently broadcasts by clandestine radio stations. General Lansdale doesn't recall anything about this.
      General Lansdale discusses "rumor campaigns" which are used to alert the people to Communist atrocities.
      SIDE TWO
      General Lansdale mentions the complicated U.S. bureaucracy which was quickly set up in Vietnam and the tendency of officials to appoint committees to deal with ideas, thus burying them.
      Finally, the two talk again about Pham Duy. He will be joined at Southern Illinois by Steve Addis.
    - Tape 125, United States, undated
      This is a recording of a seminar led, evidently, by General Lansdale. No date is given. A guest speaker, Colonel Yehuda Prihar of Israel, is featured during the particular session recorded here. Col. Prihar fought during World War II with the British and then fought in Israel's war of independence. After independence, Prihar became experienced in resisting infiltration. His talk to General Lansdale's class is on "anti-infiltration warfare."
      Prihar discusses the early days in Israel -- the importance to the displaced people of Europe to have land of their own to farm. Then he describes the problem of guerrilla infiltrators crossing the borders into Israel and terrorizing the population while gathering intelligence. Israel, therefore, devised a system of border settlements, populated by farmer-soldiers. The settlements, with their ponds and their groves of trees, block the pathways into Israel. Three "layers" of settlements are set up -- the Kibbutz, which is the strongest type of village, the cooperative, and the traditional farming community. The young people of Israel, all of whom go through military training, are educated (Prihar says "indoctrinated") to go, if they desire, to set up a new settlement. There is cooperation among villages in case of an encounter with military forces of the enemy, and each settlement is equipped to defend itself. There is a military officer of the Israeli army for each set (or sector) of settlements. Prihar details certain tactics the settlers might use. He then describes how such infiltration-resistant settlements might be set up in other countries trying to resist enemy guerrillas.
    - Tape 126, undated
      This is a recording of an undated "AWA" editorial. The speaker is not identified. He argues that the United States cannot win the war in Vietnam and that it cannot persuade Ho Chi Minh to negotiate a peace. He maintains that it is hopeless to continue, despite the technology of weaponry which the U.S. has employed against the Viet Cong, because (1) the Viet Cong have fought the Japanese, the French, and now the Americans and are willing to continue fighting; (2) the Viet Cong are capable of increasing troops and arms to meet U.S. increases; (3) the U.S. cannot compete with "Oriental patience and disregard for human life"; (4) the U.S.S.R. is determined to provide arms for the Viet Cong in order to keep the U.S. mired in this conflict; and (5) Ho Chi Minh is determined to win, even if he must retreat to the jungle and wage a guerrilla war.
      The speaker then argues that Vietnam is unlike other wars: the United States has used more fire power than it used in World War II, and "we have assembled the most formidable fighting machine in the world," but "it has not been equal to half-naked natives, and our wisdom unequal to bridging the huge gulf separating the cultures of East and West." The only "road out of the wilderness," he feels, is turning civil and military responsibilities over to the Vietnamese. He concludes that it is paternalistic to claim that the Vietnamese are not ready for this responsibility. The U.S. cannot govern Vietnam because it clearly does not understand the people and culture. A few brilliant men -- "such as General Edward Lansdale" -- understand the politics, but most U.S. leaders do not.
  - Increment, 1958-1970, undated
    Tapes formerly stored in vault.
    - Tape 127, United States, undated
      De Calula, subversive warfare speech.
    - Tape 128, United States, undated
      Lansdale, counterinsurgency speech.
    - Tapes 129-130, United States, 1958 December 3
      Lansdale, "Limited War -- Southeast Asia," speech, National War College.
    - Tape 131, United States, 1962 July 3
      Lansdale, speech, Foreign Service Institute.
    - Tapes 132-133, United States, 1970 January 28
      Music, Dolf Droge.
    - Tape 134, 1970 January 27
      Music, Middle Eastern.
- Videorecordings, 1974 (Box 94)
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Use copy reference number: 80116_v_0001652
  Film tape reels of a presentation by Lansdale relating to his experiences in Vietnam given at Hagerstown Junior College, Hagerstown, Maryland.
- Maps and Charts, undated (Map case)
- Memorabilia, 1955, 1961, 1963 (Box 98)
  - Fuerza Fluvial y Lacustre De Bolivia pennant, 1963
  - Sea Swallow pennants, badge, and pin, circa 1961
  - United States Army Caribbean Honorario pin and Jungle Expert badge, circa 1955
- Declassified Documents
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part, returned from the U.S. Department of Defense. Includes some interfiled, unclassified government records.
  - (Former) Boxes 1-2 (Box-folder 95: 1)
  - (Former) Box 3
    - Folder 1 (Box-folder 95: 2)
    - Folder 2 (Box-folder 95: 3)
    - Folder 4 (Box-folder 95: 4)
  - (Former) Box 4
    - Folders 1-8 (Box-folder 95: 5)
    - Folders 8-12 (Box-folder 95: 6)
  - (Former) Box 5 (Box-folder 95: 7)
  - (Former) Box 6
    - Folders 1-2 (Box-folder 95: 8)
    - Folder 4 (Box-folder 95: 9)
  - (Former) Box 7 (Box-folder 96: 1)
  - (Former) Box 8 (Box-folder 96: 2)
  - (Former) Box 10
    - Folders 1-19 (Box-folder 96: 3)
    - Folders 20-21 (Box-folder 96: 4)
    - Folder 22 (Box-folder 96: 5)
  - (Former) Box 11
    - Folders 1-3 (Box-folder 96: 6)
    - Folders 4-6 (Box-folder 97: 1)
    - Folders 7-9 (Box-folder 97: 2)
    - Folders 10-29 (Box-folder 97: 3)
  - (Former) Box 12 (Box-folder 97: 4)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 97: 5)